# **Christos Kapsalis**

# Full-Stack Software Developer | Software Engineer

xrikapsalis@gmail.com | +30 694 793 4771 | Athens, 16777, Greece <u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio</u>

# **Professional Summary**

**Full-stack software developer** for 8+ years of hands-on experience across the entire development lifecycle. Front-end development in **React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), CSS3, Bootstrap** and **HTML5**. Back-end development in **Node.js, Java, Lua** and **PHP**. Eager to learn new languages, technologies and undertake interesting projects. Accountable, working on schedule and comfortable working as a team member.

## **Core Skills**

**Front-end Development:** React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), Redux, PWA, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap **Back-end Development:** Node.js, Express.js, Lua, Java, Spring Framework, PHP, SQL, Bash Scripting, C

**DevOps & Deployment:** Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins

Version Control: Git, SVN

Data Formats & APIs: RESTful APIs, JSON, AJAX, XML, SVI

Testing: Unit Testing, JUnit, Robot Framework

Development Tools & Others: VS Code, Eclipse, Phpstorm, Sublime, Codecharge Studio, SQL Clients, Postman,

Browsers' Web Developer Tools, Balsamiq (Mock-ups), Wireshark, CMS, Agile

# **Work Experience**

#### Freelance Climbing Instructor & Software Development Sabbatical

November 2022 - Present

- Providing climbing instruction on a freelance basis, focusing on safety and skill development for climbers of all levels.
- Pursuing advanced full-stack development training (Zero to Mastery Academy).
- Developing projects using **React.js**, **Node.js**, and modern web technologies.
- Maintaining and expanding technical knowledge during career transition period.

#### **Senior Technical Specialist**

Nokia | Athens

December 2021 – October 2022

- Developed back-end components of Altiplano Controller, an open software GUI platform connecting other Nokia's software units via **RESTful APIs**.
- Implemented **Java-based microservices** feature with **JUnit** testing, loaded on a **Docker** container and deployed on **Kubernetes** infrastructure.
- Managed PODs configurations and orchestrated software interactions within Kubernetes environment.
- Experience in Intent development logic, microservices, Cloud based solutions, DevOps operations, Kibana search engine and Postman request engine.

#### **Software Engineer**

Nokia | Athens

 $September\ 2016-December\ 2021$ 

- Full-stack development of WebCT (2016-2021), a software that provided a GUI to administer X-Haul microwave products. Led back-end development of WebCT in Lua and DB handling with Lua-Sqlite3.
- Implemented WebCT GUI in Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap framework.
- Side project development of ASLM (2018-2021), an app that produces licenses for all X-Haul products, in **Java** with **JUnit** testing in the back-end and **React.js** in the front-end.
- Involved with the full circle of a feature's production. Creation and reviewing of feature's code, software architectural designs, Low Level Design, mock-ups, CuDo documents. Developing at least one feature per release while following a biannual release schedule.
- Peer reviewing of Code, Use Cases, Test Strategy and Test Cases.
- Applied full stack Unit Testing and debugging of code.

#### **Software Engineer**

Nokia | Athens

June 2015 – August 2016

- Full-stack development of the FMANG application, a comprehensive monitoring and configuration management system for Nokia's FlexiNG product.
- Contributed to back-end development of new features released on a biannual schedule in **Java** and **Java EE Development toolset (JSF/Primefaces, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Tomcat, Jenkins, Junit)**, while maintaining code quality through peer reviews of code.
- Development of the front-end in JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Led complete GUI redesign initiative after company's rebranding and resolved with the help of the team a critical

system-wide bug affecting application stability.

#### **E&V Tester**

Nokia | Athens October 2014 – May 2015

- Managed **CI** Test Suite of 400+ test cases for Nokia's LTE network gateway (FlexiNG).
- Implemented automated testing using **Robot Framework** with daily CI reporting.
- Enhanced testing coverage by developing new test cases and improving existing ones.

### Web Programmer/Developer

Cybertechnics Interactive Communication LTD | Athens

December 2012 - January 2014

- Full-stack development of Modus CMS using PHP, MySQL in the back-end and JavaScript, HTML and CSS in the front-end.
- Managed back-end administration and development of CMS' modules and components.
- Updating and debugging CMS' code and executed database operations, upon customers' requests.
- Implemented RAFM (Restricted Access File Manager) filesystem and integration of Ajaxplorer GUI into Modus CMS.

## **Education**

#### **Zero To Mastery Academy**

zerotomastery.io

October 2024 – Present

Attending Full-Stack Web Developer Career Path. Updating my knowledge on CSS, latest versions of JavaScript, learning React.js, Redux, PWA, Node.js with Express.js, PostgreSQL, Machine Learning API by building web apps, incorporating all these technologies.

#### **University of Piraeus**

**Piraeus** 

September 2004 – October 2011

University degree - Bachelor in <u>Digital Systems & Technology Education</u> | Computer Science

#### Stockholm University and KTH joint department

Erasmus Exchange Student Program | Knowledge Management

January 2009 - June 2009

### Languages

Greek (Native), English (Fluent), Italian (Intermediate)